JULIA WAMBUI MUIRURI

+254 724856784 | julia.muiruri@outlook.com Kenya (Thika, 5123 - 01002) https://www.linkedin.com/in/juliamuiruri/ https://github.com/julzajules

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Motivated individual with problem solving and teamwork as my core competencies with a great attention to detail. Experienced in various programs at the Microsoft Africa Development Center and involvement in structuring programs like the Game of Learners Season and Clinics that provide technical skilling opportunities for the student developer community. Lifelong learner and a responsible advocate with exceptional soft and technical skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Game of Learners Ambassador – (6-month part-time contract)

Microsoft Africa Development Center

Onboard learners to agile delivery of software and offering logistic planning support, providing learning opportunities to 150+ student developers in Software Engineering Fundamentals and involvement of 60+ students in software development from Kenya and Nigeria. Actively contributing to the management of the program's website on GitHub.

Industrial Attaché – (3 months)

Microsoft Africa Development Center

Building a system that helps organizational admins manage programs on Visual Studio Code using JavaScript and TypeScript, MongoDB Compass, and Postman for API management. (Project in progress: Ndovu Network) on Azure Web Service. Responsible for managing the project and communicating the system's architecture and user stories to decide on packages, project starters, libraries, and contribute to the frontend development of the project.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Gold Microsoft Learn Student Ambassador

Microsoft

Sept 2019 - Dec 2021

Collaborate with global leaders, founding 5 technology-oriented communities in various universities with 2000+ members continuously learning about technology and working on projects aimed at solving real world problems.

Team Lead - Game of Learners

Microsoft Africa Development Center

June 2020

Led a team in critically analyzing a problem and implementing a solution using different technologies and frameworks, leveraging Microsoft Azure and collaborative product delivery using Agile development methods on Azure DevOps. Built a health-based application providing medical procedures to users and won the people's choice award.

Founder

Imagine Cup Community Kenya August 2020 - Present

Initiated a program that amplifies Microsoft Imagine Cup in Kenya, building a community and facilitated events, publishing of 10+ blogs with 500+ students involved in program activities.

Founder

MLSA P2P Mentoring Sept 2021 - Present

Founded a peer-to-peer mentoring program with 130+ students actively learning and sharing knowledge and opportunities in the technology industry with Microsoft Student Ambassadors. One of the goals is to recruit students into the Ambassador program.

SKILLS & TOOLS

- Creative and Critical Thinking
- Communication Skills
- Time Management
- Software Architecture
- Program/Project Management
- Microsoft Power Platform
- Azure DevOps/GitHub
- Visual Studio Code/Visual Studio
- Frontend (React + Material UI)
- JavaScript
- Microsoft Azure

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technology May 2018 - Dec 2021

Dedan Kimathi University of Technology

CERTIFICATIONS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Microsoft Certified: Power Platform Fundamentals

<u>See Credentials</u> (January 2022)

Software Architecture: University of Alberta, Coursera (December 2021)

Foundations of Project Management Certification, Coursera (September 2021)

Runners Up: Imagine Cup EMEA Regional Finals

<u>Project now Startup</u> (March 2020)

Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
See Credentials
(October 2019)